[Music]
w
good good evening good day everybody and
welcome to the ask abijit show I hope
you're all doing very well to those of
you who are returning viewers thank you
very much for returning and I really
really appreciate your viewership I do
not take it for granted I know how much
of a privilege it is for a single person
to pay attention to you so I really
appreciate that and those of you who are
new viewers welcome to the show take a
look and maybe you'll learn something
from it hopefully uh what's the purpose
of the show is to answer your questions
uh so how do you ask questions some may
wonder you ask questions in today's live
stream in the live chat you ask
questions in the live chat and in
tomorrow's live stream you can ask
questions for that live stream in the
comments so that's how how it is and how
do you ensure that your questions get
picked up ask good questions ask
questions whose answers will benefit all
the viewers that's that's what this is
all about so uh yeah that's about it and
let's see who all is there on the live
stream I can see lots of people uh
geopolitical du Anish pray Kumar pan
Kumar Singh G Smita Mishra niharika
Gupta brain visha Rohit a tagat Karan
Hala machaa Satish Johan Rohan Gad
Amisha Mishra hello anahita molana
something Vishnu mohanan dsha bavar
kayal pray Paul from Kolkata hello Anish
pushkar Ray soham Kar
anurag deep Ahuja sua Pavan tanni Zub
eung hello uh mahish rakit Mishra bosar
threat Ripper sankit ganor crazy brain
hello banab Bonia rajat Chopra hello ram
ram G pan Kumar Singh ragir solanki bar
editz ritwick yui shashwat mukarji rajat
Chopra again tagat Karan and uh Tushar
Kori Anand Chandra sikaran Omar Sher
wadar pushkar R sha
jaaj lit Tani xas Yus zus her on Wheels
Shan shayu
goami and lots of other people feminist
Slayer Rish Dash Gupta Rah Rahul sud
gorov and everyone else okay so so yeah
so let's take some questions please ask
me your best questions sometimes I get
comments that I ask you so many
questions you didn't pick a single
question and sometimes I get the
complaint that I only take questions
from some people look ask me questions
that whose answer will benefit whose
answers will benefit benefit the large
audience everybody who's watching who's
watching live right now and who will
watch in when it's no longer live so ask
your best questions ask questions that
that interest me that make me think and
if you know me you'll you probably know
what kind of questions I like to take so
ask me your best questions if you want
me to answer right I would like to
answer everyone's questions but the
objective over here is not to answer
everybody's questions the objective is
to give some information and to to some
extent educate the audience the viewers
that's the the the objective of this
show so ask me your best questions
please that's what I would like to tell
you now let's take
questions uh prna Ames says is it GIS
Khan or is it chenis Khan it is chenis
Khan that's how the Mongol say it look
it doesn't matter how the English or the
British or the American say it or the
French say it what truly matters is what
the Mongols say that is the correct
pronunciation so how do I put this up
one second um um um let me put this up
it's c h i n g g i s h a n it's actually
this way check it out uh will it appear
somewhere yeah this is the correct
spelling that kind of approximates the
correct pronunciation kingis KH that's
how the Mongols say his name
uh and then there are so many examples
like this okay uh I mean so many names
of Indian kings and queens and name
places Etc are mangled beyond
recognition by the English language and
what the British and the English have
written them as for example there is a
city called Baroda what is Baroda it's
vodra right what is Adam's Bridge it is
rahasu what is Adam's Peak it is not
Adams Peak it is something else in Sri
Lanka what is peing it's not PE speaking
it's paging what is I mean there are a
Millions what is Mount Everest it's
Sagar MAA or chma in in the Tibetan
language it's not it's not Mount Everest
so we have to decolonize ourselves and
uh yeah so it's not gangis Khan or chis
Khan It's chingis Khan that is the
correct way of uh saying his
name uh some RI says why do you not
speak Hindi in this channel this is an
English Channel I and why do I generally
not do live streams in Hindi and
generally why is everything in English
most of it the it's because I'm more
comfortable in English you see this
called This is called mental
colonization I keep on I I often draw
your attention to this that we are all
mentally colonized in one way or the
other in in multiple ways and we don't
realize it at least I realize it and I'm
saying it openly I am mentally colonized
I am more comfortable in a foreign
language that's how I was brought up
that's what the education system Etc did
to me so I'm more comfortable more
proficient in a foreign language than
in the Hindi the Hindi language May
Hindi be TI but and there are other
issues also because I I learned Hindi in
know in a in I picked up Hindi from
various places and various sources
including movies and TV and the streets
and so on and I don't like speak
speaking a mangled up corrupted language
I like to speak whatever language I use
I like to speak with good grammar and
vocabulary and when it comes to the
Hindi language it's not really it's got
It's got words from so many foreign
sources that I would rather not honor
because that happened through
colonization and
oppression there are so many foreign
words in the Hindi language I would
rather speak a more sanskritized Hindi
but I not that
proficient so there are multiple reasons
why I don't speak Hindi okay and it's
not really our national language the
actual civilizational language is
sanskrit which no one speaks everybody
has a mattering of understanding of
Sanskrit the vocabulary Etc but none of
us can actually speak the language
neither unfortunately can I speak it I
have some understanding of Sanskrit I've
done some study and all I would if I had
the option of doing it I would actually
speak Sanskrit instead of Hindi but I'm
not that good in Sanskrit and my Hindi
isn't that great I mean it's definitely
possible I can certainly go anywhere in
the country and speak good enough Hindi
to be understood really well but you you
get the point right so that's why I
speak in
English I know there are benefits to
speaking Hindi if I do a full-time Hindi
Channel I I'm sure I'll get 10 times the
viewership I'm getting here I you know I
I know that but well so that's why I
don't do it right these are the reasons
why I don't do that now next RMS says
India is doing very well in the chess
Olympiad they're first in both open and
women right now I believe why can't we
do the same with the
Olympics look chess if you want to learn
chess and become really good a chess it
doesn't cost you a
lot let's say you are a child in
a middle class or low middle class
family one earning member of the family
let's say hypothetical your father earns
a reasonable amount of money and
everybody else is dependent so you it's
hard for most Indians because most
Indians are in this category it's hard
for most Indians to make ends meet a
shortage of money your one medical
condition away from financial disaster
at any given point in time as a family
in that situation how do you expect your
parents to invest
in any sport that you would be
interested in let's say you want to
become a cricketer you know it you need
to buy gear for that let's say you want
to be a batsman or a bats girl whatever
you want to be you got to buy the the
the gear right the gloves and the
whatever else the protective equipment
and the pads and at least one bat a
helmet Etc elbow guards if you want to
be a bowler I suppose they it's easier
to be a bowler of course but most
Indians want want to be a bat want to
bat so there is that if you want to and
then you need access to training
facilities a good coach and all that it
costs a lot of money to provide for
these things you want to be a shooter
it's going to cost you lacks of rupees a
month possibly because or at least the
investment the onetime investment the
the the rifle that you need or or the
pistol that you need it's it's going to
be quite expensive plus you need the
ammunition plus you need a shooting
range all of these things cost so much
money you want to be in 10 player it
costs a lot of money
so when you take all that into account
and you then you think about chess chess
cost you nothing you can get all the
education chess education you want
online all you need is to you don't even
need a chess okay you need a chess board
and the pieces that doesn't cost you
much it's a it's a small amount of money
you can even create makeshift chess
pieces out of out of whatever and draw a
chess board on a piece of paper if if if
it comes to that so chess is so easy I
mean it's it's it doesn't cost any money
to learn chess it's it's almost a no
investment sport so that's why Indians
will do really well at that because we
are still unfortunately a low income
nation and it's going to be a while
before India becomes a middle income
nation and starts getting better at
other sports so that's why we don't do
well in the
Olympics uh and of course when it comes
to the sporting associations I don't
even go into the alleged corruption and
whatnot the shinanigans that goard there
are so many factors okay Merit India is
a nation that the the system the system
the governance system and and the
establishment doesn't respect
Merit and that's why this is something
these are things that artificially keep
India down so that's why chess is
something you don't need any in any real
investment to start learning chess and
you can practice against people you can
practice against uh non human opponents
online so you can get really good if you
have the the ingredients the right
ingredients that's why India does well
in chess chess and you got so many
youngsters coming out of essentially
nowhere almost right so many talented
youngsters coming up girls boys so good
to see so at least we are forced to be
reckoned with in chess and I think we're
going to sweep most championships going
forward that that's good and hopefully
in the future we get we get we become a
middle income nation and we we are able
to see parents investing decent amounts
of money in other sports as well for
their children's development so that's
the
reason McLovin says do you think this
government will finish this term I think
it could be
iffy
yeah uh look the current government as
we all know is a coalition
government uh it it the BJP doesn't have
on its own enough seats to
have a majority in Parliament what's how
much did they get 240 or something
something like that so they have to
depend on others other parties they they
are in a coalition government these
other parties can at some point in time
in the future possibly be be influenced
to withdraw support maybe for internal
reasons maybe because of external
factors let's let's put it that so I
think it's going to be
difficult this is a much weaker Modi
government it's a much diminished prime
minister that we are seeing and he he is
gonna perform he's gonna have to perform
this time other see this is probably his
last term Mr Modi and if he wants his
party to win the next election 2029
which will be good for the country
otherwise we we be cooked otherwise
right he's going to have to pull all the
I mean he'll have to make this his best
term and he'll also have to ensure that
the right person is the face of the next
election is is is that going to be
possible to do all that I certainly hope
so it's it's
uh it's it's going to be difficult very
difficult I mean if you don't have a
majority in Parliament everything
becomes much more difficult so I I'm not
some
political pundit uh analyst or whatever
I look at history geopolitics and
science I don't really look at into the
internal politics but internal politics
does matter at the geopolitical level as
well so I I hope Mr modi's government
finishes its five-year term I think it's
going to be difficult and I think it's
very important for him to to make major
major bring in major reforms in the
country and take the country
significantly forward in this this
whatever time he has otherwise it's
going to be a disaster for his party in
the next elections and one of the
keys to the political continuity is what
Mr Modi and his government do about
Manipur because the thing the way things
are going it may be the end it could
very well
derail I mean you
know it will unless things are set right
in Manipur it will very very strongly
affect the kind of confidence that
people have in the government Now by now
see the the problem in Manipur began
more than a year ago now people are able
to see what the real issue is something
I've been speaking about for more than a
year so unless these things addressed it
will be very hard for the BJP to win the
next election and then we go back to
Coalition politics and that's the
essentially the end of India we'll never
be great if that happens
so okay the mangang says Manipur crisis
okay let's talk about Manipur that's one
question by DP mangang GE political dub
also says what's the current situation
in Manipur how long will native Hindus
survive there if the government does not
do anything right
now I mean you know
I've uh the way the government has
handled the issue thus far is extremely
disappointing and I think this is
something that could essentially end the
political career of Mr
Modi thus far his uh his handling of
Manipur has been
abysmal to be very fair to Mr Modi he
did not it is this this crisis was not
started by him it's not his fault that
this situation happened the cookie
infiltration into into Manipur and all
that that that these pieces on the
chessboard have been put in place for a
very long time it started in the 19th
century and it continued after the
1947 independence of India successive
governments of India brought in more and
more cookie infiltrators into India and
gave them citizenship you see cookies in
very high positions in the bureaucracy
and all that very very bad situation so
Mr Modi did not create the problem but
he he did not see this
coming he was caught completely unawares
and for one plus year he has not had any
idea what to do with the situation now
we can see they're bringing taking out
Assam rifles from from
Manipur yeah after more than one year I
think they they seem to be waking up to
the to what the real root cause of all
the problems is I'm not saying the Assam
rifles itself is the root cause but uh
taking the Assam rifles out of Manipur
is a right step in the right direction
I'll just leave it at that so uh the
current situation is very bad imagine
the capital city of a state of India is
being bombed by drones whatever state
you're living in Imagine a situation
like that
happening drones operated by Foreign
infiltrators are bombing your Capital
City dropping bombs on on your capital
city that is a state of
War right that's something that Manipur
is is
seeing and what on Earth is the
government doing about
it to be very fair the
situation Manipur you know before the
BJP government came to power in Manipur
whichever year it was in the 2010s when
Mr ban Singh became uh chief minister
before that I think the people of
Manipur have already forgotten how
things were before
that
encounters every day
curfew the moment the light starts
getting dim in the evening and curfew
until morning bombs bomb blasts every
day uh
insurgence shooting people and stuff the
situation in Manipur was abysmal there
was no nightlife people did not go out
of their of their homes after after dark
there was afpa everywhere a ASA was
imposed in Manipur in
1958 it it is still on in some places in
Manipur I think they they're imposing in
more parts of Manipur aspa is a failure
in Manipur aspa is something you use for
a short sharp period of time and then
you solve the problem since 58 1958
offsp is in forth in Manipur clearly
offsp has
failed but offsp is designed to to allow
the security forces to succeed then
what's going on who was in power all
these years in Manipur and how did
things get so bad so so I would not lay
I would be I would rather be very fair
and say that the BJP government did not
create the problem they actually tried
to solve the problem things were very
good for five years five six years after
Mr biren Singh came to power I would not
say all the problems were soled but
things are so much better econ the
economy in Manipur was taking off um
people were able to go out at night for
the first time in decades and so on and
then this happens May 3 right 2023 and
the government is got completely
unawares and offu how did this happen
the cookies were supposed to be good
right so um the native Hindus in Manipur
are under attack they're under
siege they are allowed to stay in only
about 6% of their of the territory of
the state of Manipur it's a disastrous
horrible
situation and the things you do for
electoral gains well it comes back to
bite you in the
wherever it bites you back doesn't it uh
now the solution to the problem is
outside of India it's outside of Indian
Territory and this is not some Law and
Order issue please understand this is a
geopolitical issue because the puppet
master who is behind all of this is the
biggest power on the
planet they want to create an artificial
Christian Nation out of parts of Manipur
out of mizoram out of parts of
Bangladesh and out of large parts of
Burma cooki land for Christ and the US
is behind this even
China is on the back foot here so the
Civil War that's happening in Burma
that's essentially a proxy war between
the US and
China the the the establishment the the
government that's been in power for so
many decades it has historically been
Pro China the burmes Hun
government and the Civil War is by all
these various rag tag trib outfits that
have somehow unlimited access to arms
and ammunition and who are fighting the
burmes government who certainly are all
coordinated and they have great
leadership and tactics and strategies
how does a rag tag bunch of half naked
tribals suddenly acquire All These Arms
ammunition all these strategies tactics
out of the best playbooks something is
is in play and this is designed to
affect China as well as India could you
believe
it not China to that much of extent
because there's no terrorism happening
on Chinese
territory but India well we are under
siege so the situation is very bad the
solution to the problem lies outside of
India lies in bur's
territory and will the Modi government
have the the fortitude let's say to
solve the problem the solution is a
military solution outside of Indian
Territory of course it's going to cause
problems because the superpower will
then uh you know make all kinds of
allegations against India human rights
blah blah blah so I think the only
solution is if you treat this as a pilot
project with another aligned Nation
another aligned power we have to figure
out whether the power can be aligned
with
us um yeah but so this situation has
exposed
the incredible power asymmetry and
disparity between the US and India this
and what happened in
Bangladesh it's nothing personal that
the Americans have against India nothing
personal at all they just ensuring that
they're that the power equilibrium Power
Balance is in their favor absolutely
nothing personal against India there's
no hatred of India or anything it's just
that if you will not alive with us then
we will make sure that we put the right
pieces on the chessboard in the
subcontinent and there's nothing you can
do about it they're demonstrating it to
India so what does India do about this
because our own our sovereignties at
take over here this kind of demonstrates
to you my friends that India is not a
fully Sovereign Nation I I will I will
be getting comments right now about the
chavda index right the
geopolitical U rankings of of
Nations the hard power rankings I have
not released it thus far because I'm
going to have to have to amend it one of
the major factors that I take into
consideration in the calculations is
sovereignty and thus far I had treated
India as a fully Sovereign Nation with a
sovereignty index of
one I probably will have to downgrade
India's sovereignty ranking not a fully
Sovereign Nation because if you have
your one of your states that is under
siege by foreigners and you're not able
to do anything for more than one year
then you're not a Sovereign Nation so I
think uh I'll have to revise my view of
India's sovereignty India is not a fully
Sovereign Nation and I
think there are many more examples of
that I mean there's rampant industrial
scale conversions happening in this
country and the government is doing
nothing about it there is large scale
industrial scale illegal immigration
infiltration happening into India
Bangladesh's ringas cookies the
government is doing nothing about it
maybe it's unable or unwilling to do it
I don't know and there are so many of
our U institutions National institutions
that are compromised and infiltrated by
Foreign agents
allegedly and has the government done a
thing about that in in the past decade
not so much so I would say I will have
to be realistic and I have to downgrade
India's sovereignty ranking which would
push India further down the top 10 if we
remain in the top 10 in the global hard
power rankings but I've got to be
realistic if I put out an index that is
all fantasy and La La Land then what's
the point of doing that so I'm going to
have to amend that and Manipur is the is
the is the shining example of how India
is not fully Sovereign the government of
India is not able to take care of the
interests of its own
citizens
okay rather dispiriting isn't it but it
is what it
is okay now let's talk
about okay is asks this question what do
you think of Israel's recent pager
attack
onah uh Anish is asking that over and
over again so Anish I've got your
question and
uh um okay so let's take that question
yeah so first of all how do we know it's
Israel that's behind
this has Israel officially uh claimed
credit taken credit for this operation
that happened has the Hamad the mosad
taken credit for
this I know that the that on social
media various Israeli citizens and even
reasonably high ranking people are kind
of gloating about
this but do we have any official
evidence that Israel is behind
this and does it mean because they have
not officially agreed or accepted that
they have been this does it mean that
Israel is not behind it it's neither
this nor that here's the
deal so we know what happened in
Lebanon Hezbollah right all these
Hezbollah operators were were carrying
pagers the pagers blew up it they beeped
and if once these guys removed it it
blew up in their face if they didn't
remove it it blew up in
their the belt
area below the
belt there is that apparently the the
Iranian Ambassador also had the same
thing happened to him apparently he was
also carrying a pagure and then the next
day other devices start
exploding so this is an incredible
operation that's been carried out so
many questions are still
unanswered do I believe Israel is behind
this I believe Israel is behind this but
I don't believe that Israel is the only
Power behind this please understand
that I think this operation was too
extensive
an infiltration of of Global Supply
chains for only Israel to be involved in
this I believe the superpower
itself would be involved in this to some
extent at C at certain levels I'm
talking about obviously the United
States I think look I don't have
evidence but I have a little bit of
brain I think this could be a
collaborative effort or operation
between the United States and Israel
that's what I
think and it's it's incredible the way
the entire Supply chains were
compromised infiltrated taken over the
pagers are allegedly no they're not
allegedly they are definitely uh
manufactured by a company in Taiwan now
the Taiwan company says that there's a
company in Europe that has the license
to manufacture these pagers in the name
of the Taiwanese
company so apparently these pagers were
uh manufactured probably in Europe as
per the complaint of the of the
Taiwanese company then they were routed
to to to Lebanon but clearly somewhere
something happened
now these explosions they were certainly
powerful enough to blow people's fingers
off blow people's uh body parts off some
in some cases uh blind people and all
some deaths also have occurred so pretty
power reason ably powerful
explosions now what caused the
explosions was it simply the lithium ion
batteries uh exploding or was there
something inserted into the lithium ion
batteries was a small amount of some
other
explosive uh inserted into the lithium
ion batteries and how was it done we
know that lithium if it is overheated in
whatever under certain conditions
lithian ion batteries are known to burn
we know that they burn but they don't
explode in this manner and even if they
burn explosively the explosion isn't
something that will blow people's
fingers and body parts Etc
off or have they found a way to make
lithan ion batteries behave in that
manner or did they insert some kind of
substance some kind of explosive
material if they did insert some kind of
explosive material that must have been a
really powerful explosive not the
standard RDX that Indians Indian experts
like to talk about it's not plastic it's
not the RDX that the Indian experts like
to talk about it's something completely
unknown thus
far and the next day after the pager
blasts other devices started exploding
iPhones started
exploding do you know the kind of
Spectre this
raises governments worldwide are going
to take very very serious measures now
they're going to have to rethink airport
boarding boarding
procedures they're going to have to
rethink everything thing do you I have
seen so many world leaders without
taking names who use
iPhones isn't this a message that the
Whoever has carried out they're sending
a message to leaders all across the
world your phones are not merely
listening to you
24x7 they can be used to take you
out that's the message they're sending
to people across the
world so generally we
know almost everyone in the world today
carries a cell phone right it's with you
it's on you on your person almost 24 by7
when you when you sleep it's right next
to your pillow or wherever it is it's
always right next to you if your cell
phone is a Chinese made cell phone the
Chinese government is listening to you
and taking all your data we know
that if it's a Taiwanese or or or or or
South Korean cell phone
or Western cell phone
then the US government is listening to
you 24 by7 and taking all your data now
they may not be listening to you like as
a person listening to you but everything
is being recorded and on and if needed
they'll listen to you and in some cases
in the case of some individuals you know
high value individuals they may actually
be listening to you in real time as in a
human being may be listening to you in
real time so we know that the Chinese
and the
US they have been eeves dropping on the
entire world and taking all you know
scraping all the data and so on but now
we have realized that at least the West
has the ability to take out individuals
through the cell phones or whatever
other
devices it
is going to change the way security
agencies look at everything it's going
to put a whole new fear of the Gods in
the minds and hearts of world leaders
it's going to have it's going to cause a
whole rethink of everything security
measures when it comes to world leaders
and important people airport procedures
everything it's a message they've sent
to the world and also they've taken out
hisbah and and what effect does it have
on hisbah it's a disaster for hisbah
they don't know what to use now can I
use my toaster can I use my blender can
I use my air
conditioner they have no idea what to do
now
paralyzed they can't they don't know
whom to trust clearly there were people
Crum Within hisbah who were compromised
clearly if you think about it there are
there are whoever did this has assets
within the within the hisbah leadership
at what levels we have no idea high low
maybe multiple levels so the hisbah
operatives hisbah theah operatives don't
know whether they can trust their
leaders if they are being told to go and
do certain things
somewhere am I being sent to my
death and the hisbah leaders have no
they they know no longer know whom to
trust in their minions down the line
lower down the
ranks and imagine the kind of effect
this has on the
morale of hisbah operatives so it's a
tremendous victory for Israel clearly
tremendous
Victory uh October 7 last year was their
worst intelligence
failure
this will do it does not
entirely uh you know wash away the
blemish to their reputation but it it
has this will do this will go a long way
towards restoring the reputation of the
Israeli intelligence
services so yeah that's what I think
about this lots of questions that will
remain unanswered maybe for decades how
they did this what kind of explosive was
in involved in this or was it the
lithium batteries themselves that can be
engineered to
be remotely detonated lots of questions
are
unanswered but yeah big victory for the
Israelis and big
victory for the us as well I'm sure
because the US gets to tell the world
indirectly look this is what we can do
to
anybody so that's how I see
it
okay um jitu chetri says what's the role
of Marco poloo in KU victory over the
Yuan Dynasty excuse me sir KU
Khan belonged to the Yuan
Dynasty okay let's Google Yuan
Dynasty shall
we let's Google Yuan Dynasty it's a
conquest Dynasty started by Shri chingis
Khan Yuan Dynasty look what does
Wikipedia which is not Rel always
reliable what does it have to say the
Yuan dynasty was a Mongol Le Imperial
Dynasty of China and a successor state
to the Mongol Empire it was established
by KU
Khan the fifth Kagan emperor of the
Mongol Empire from the borjigin clan and
so on so forth okay so this dynasty that
you are referring to it was kubl Khan's
own
Dynasty and it is said that KU Khan
established it but KU Khan gave the
credit to his grandfather chingis khad
and according to the Mongols the first
emperor of the Yuan dynasty was chingis
khad himself the second was
uh what was his name jingis Khan's
son ogod ogod Khan and the third was KU
and so on so Kubla Khan did not defeat
the Yuan Dynasty kubl Khan essentially
founded the Yuan
Dynasty right and he was the emperor of
all China a Mongol Emperor so please
understand how things actually are Kubla
Khan did not well he had no great
victories except for unifying China and
all that the great victories were were
done by his grandfather and and his
uncle grandfather chis Khan Uncle ogod
Khan and KU Khan essentially inherited
China U when China became available
after the death of OG long long story
about all the politics that ensues in
dynasties and Empires and so on and
Marco poloo was just an observer in his
uh Court an Italian Merchant who had
traveled all the way to China and he
wrote about kubl Khan and so on so forth
and that's the thing I don't know that
there is some some some TV series right
in which uh they they give a lot more
credit to Marco PO for God knows what
stuff I haven't watched it I don't
really watch that sort of thing but uh
so that's the deal okay goblak Khan was
the founder of the Yuan Dynasty which
was a Mongol Dynasty that that ruled
China other says how can expressways
transform India how can can this speed
up India's economic growth economic
growth by bringing in manufacturing
companies look the more interconnected a
nation is and the faster transportation
is the better the economy will perform
the Japanese economy it really took off
after the introduction of the shinh
kanen train system system the bullet
trains I think in the' 60s early 60s
onwards that
really made the whole of Japan
accessible to uh its citizens you could
travel from the north to the south of
Japan in just a couple of hours
essentially that's how fast these bullet
trades are I'm just I maybe over
exaggerating a bit but you get the point
so when you have a nation that is
Thoroughly interconnected let's say I am
sitting in let's say baneswar in in in
orisa and I wake up in the morning and I
say I feel like going to theer in
Assam is it possible for me that morning
to take my phone book a ticket or bus
train whatever let's say bus or train
let's say bus book a ticket for theer
for a bus to theer or a train let's say
is it possible or will I have to be put
on some waiting list which will go on
for weeks and all all that sort of stuff
so if you are if you have a country that
that has that gives you the option of
doing that wherever you are in the
country you wake up in the morning and
you decide on on a whim that I want to
go to the other end of the country some
small town and if your country gives you
the options of of booking a ticket on
the spot and in a couple of hours being
being on a train or or whatever that
country's economy I promise you will'll
be doing
superb so expressways can transform
India's economy they will not bring a
ched in for the
people you understand they'll transform
India's economy not they will not
transform living standards they will
certainly spring uh speed up India's
economic growth the more high speed
expressways you have with hopefully no
toall
tool I think these Tool uh uh tool boots
and all they slow things down and I
think the government should should
absorb the cost of all these things
actually that's what I believe but
whatever at least we have these
expressways uh so the more express way
you have that connect that interconnect
India the the better India's economy
will doing we need expressways we need
highspeed rail systems all across the
country we need more and more airports
every town of India should be should be
connected by airports and so on the more
we do this the faster econom India's
economy will grow but it will not change
your living conditions for that you need
your local governments to wake the hell
up and they want right now at least most
places not not much changes happened in
the past 10 years
okay let's see what else we
have Hala Macha Hal Hal Macha says will
there be a cold war 2.0 between China
and the us in the future um excuse me
Cold War 2.0 is here we are in the
middle of Cold War 2.0 it's not going to
be there in the future we are in that
it's it's there right
now there's a whole trade and tariff war
going on between in the US and China
there's a whole bifurcation of the
global order that's happening right now
of course wherever as ordinary people
sitting wherever we are we see no
difference in our daily lives
right you wake up have breakfast go to
work 2our commute you spend 10 12 hours
in your office you come back to home
another 2hour commute you crash into
your bed and go to sleep next day you
rinse and repeat rinse and repeat and
maybe if you're lucky
Sunday you can spend some time with with
family or whatever that's typically how
you spend your life if you're a student
it's the same grind every single day of
memorization and and being grilled by
your teachers and doing whatever you do
as students so you don't see what's
happening outside but there is a cold
war happening right now between the US
and
China uh the American it started with
with
Trump trump started it president Trump
when he was in power in the US he was an
office in the US it was know in power
but he started the trade and tar of war
and it's it's and Biden's go regime or
whoever is running the Biden regime they
continued that they they they took it
further and the Chinese responded
ralated whatever way they can so there
is this this thing going on right now
and after 2022 the Ukraine special
military operation Russia and China kind
of coaled into a single block from the
Western perspective obviously there are
big differences in one we'll not go into
the details so there is that and there
are nations like North Korea Iran Syria
so many other others that are kind of on
that side so you're seeing a bifurcation
of the world order the Eastern block
which is Russia China and Plus+ the
bricks is an example of that many
nations want to be on board of that
so the the the bricks Plus or or Russia
China plus access or Alliance you
whatever you call it would like to
create a separate World Order
separate from the US us-led World Order
which the Americans like to call the
rules based International order there
are no rules in that whatever the
Americans say is is the rule on that day
but that's the nature of geopolitics
that's how the world has always been run
nothing has changed the most powerful
Nation decides the rules and everybody
else has to follow the rules that's the
rules way based world order so there we
seeing a bifurcation of the world order
so the cold war is here
please wake up it's here you're seeing
you know the Americans have have imposed
these sanctions on the Chinese the
semiconductor sanctions they've imposed
every single sanction in the book on
Russia isn't that a cold
war so it's it's ongoing it's right it's
happening right now as we speak and we
are kind of in the middle
India which side do we take well we'll
take the side of whoever is best for us
and right now the Americans aren't
really good for us they are causing
Mayhem in our
neighborhood with the objective of
destabilizing India and and and and
slowing down India's economic growth so
what can I
say Vikram geopolitical says what are
your views on Iran's religious leaders
recent comments on India and call
calling it an enemy of
Islam I think it's unfortunate and
unnecessary and pointless and
counterproductive
why do India and Iran or why do Iran and
India need to be on on bad terms I don't
understand why you would want to have
that what's the
point what does Iran get out of this by
antagonizing
India what what purpose is served by
this I don't understand
it what do I think is behind this I
think the Chinese are behind
this I think the Chinese look the
Chinese and the Iranians have a 25-year
strategic agreement and the Chinese are
investing billions maybe hundreds of
billions of dollars worth of money into
into Iran's overall economy mainly for
purchasing reasonably cheap
oil and the Iranians need the money the
Iranians need uh China on their side
and I think considering all that maybe
China is behind this
they may have instructed Iran to make
this statement now why would China do
this right not not right now China is
all conciliatory towards India isn't it
in case you haven't noticed all their
statements are rather positive the
global times has has given up its
strident you know that strident tone
towards
India they even published an article
about India's foreign minister and very
rapidly deleted it so that they don't
offend India the Chinese on their own
are are being very very positive very
conciliatory towards India because it
may be that India and China may need to
cooperate on a on a variety of matters
because both of us are facing the heat
from the
US
so the Chinese always like to play
games
okay so one of the major impediments
towards an India China better
relationship not reconciliation but
better relationship is Chinese China's
Behavior and the Chinese will have to
normalize once again the situation in
the northern border the India Tibet
border they uh they to withdraw from
some forward positions they've occupied
since 2020 and so on so forth and that's
a progress that's something that's still
ongoing apparently it's happening on an
urgent basis but that kind of is is a
step back it's a walk back it's kind of
a loss of face to some extent for China
so they'll try and needle India through
other means so I think I have no
evidence to back this up but I think the
Chinese are behind the Iranian statement
and I think from Iran's perspective it's
completely pointless needless
counterproductive India and Iran should
be on good terms it it makes sense for
India and Iran to be on good terms but
here we have it so I
think it's it's completely it's very
unfortunate there was no need for them
to do this I mean what
so I think it was really really
unfortunate and pointless and counter
productive Swati Chandra says recent
Kashmir elections what are the positives
from geopolitical view
none I get the feeling that India the
government of India was pressurized into
doing
this there was no need for these
elections but here we are we're going to
have elections and whenever the results
come out I don't think this is good for
India
um ladak is now a union territory and
Jammu and Kashmir are also Union
territory or something right so why do
you and they're not supposed to have an
assembly
uh it's it's going to bring back the
old forces in power the the anti-india
forces what should have happened is jamu
Kashmir and ladak should have been
trifurcated and all three should have
been declared union
territories Now by having an assembly
and all that you're going to have the
same old tired faces back in some kind
of power and maybe they'll try and find
a way of of attempting to repeal to
bring back article 370 and all that this
is like going
backwards there was no need for this I
think the government of India has been
pressurized coerced into doing this and
maybe
certain Indian institutions
themselves are responsible for this so
there are no positives in my opinion
from The geopolitical View we can see
that this this government Modi 3.0 is a
much weaker
government and these are not
good developments for
India okay
um let me try and scroll through some
questions
and
Cricket um okay let us let's see this
with man say since childhood I've been
able to see the root causes of problems
and share an understanding of History
similar to
yours how can I use this intellect for
bat if it seems to of no use look if you
have this sort of understanding you can
use use it for serving the nation only
if you're in a position of
power without that you're an ordinary
citizen in we have 1.4 billion of us
isn't it so you may have some special
talent it's it's very rare for people to
have special talents but if you have a
special talent you have to find a way to
position yourself to place yourself in a
position of power only then can you use
the level that power gives you to to
serve the country in in a in a suitable
way um so that's the answer you have to
be in a position of power to use this
intellect and this ability for the for
the cause of the nation otherwise you're
one of the ordinary citizens like
everybody
else okay ainash says why is the chicken
neck Corridor so
thin did it had GP regions I don't know
what that means the chicken neck
Corridor okay let's let's take a look at
the map oh we haven't opened the map yet
it's almost 1 hour in here's the map oh
okay let's go to the chicken neck
Corridor the silly Siliguri Corridor why
is it so thin it's about 20 about 2 to
23 met kilometers across right 24 it
depends on how you how you measure it
less than 25 km it's a strategic choke
point it's a very vulnerable uh Point
geographically for India strategically
and if any enemy wants to uh cut off the
Far East of India from the rest of India
that's what he would want to take out
that's what you would want to attack the
Siliguri Corridor so why is this cigor
Corridor the so-called chicken's neck so
thin it's because your so-called
founding
fathers accepted this map of
India there was no need to accept this
map of India there's no need to accept
the partition of India and if you want
to accept all these things then you
could have done it on your terms but no
so these individuals who are portrayed
as our founding fathers and leaders of
the nation and all they accepted this
map of India and they have saddled you
all with this gigantic
problem that's why it's so thin there
was no need to accept it and today I'm
not sure if the government of India is
powerful enough to to change the map at
this day at this point in time it would
make a lot of sense to change the map by
incorporating rangapur and Raj Shahi
into into
bhat we should do that but probably we
are not strong enough to do that why
what do I mean by that do I mean that
the Bangladesh military is too powerful
India is too powerful for India's Army
no that's not what I
mean what I mean is that Bangladesh is
now East Pakistan it is a vasal state of
the US and if you lay a finger on on the
Bangladesh is today the Americans will
intervene and and make life very
difficult for India so
India India bhat is a very large and
reasonably powerful nation in the
subcontinent but it is surrounded on all
directions by either hostile Nations or
proxy powers proxies of other other more
powerful Nations and that's why India
has always been despite having such a
great geographical position a nation
that has underperformed and punched
below its weight and we have had such
wonderful governments that when we had
the opportunity to to to do things we
did not take those opportunities we had
decades in which we could have
constructed roads all the way into
southeast Asia from places like Manipur
nagaland missam Etc we did not bother to
do that
ever why don't we have ruls why don't we
have a rail line to
Singapore passing through Manipur or
missor or nagaland why don't we have a
road all the way to Bangkok from let's
say mo in Manipur or nagaland or
wherever you want it to be why don't we
have a road Network rail network that
connects India to Southeast Asia our
governments had decades to do this
invest in these things we never did that
so we are like a landlocked country so
it's not just our so-called founding
fathers who are to blame it's all the
governments who have come after that all
all okay I'm not excluding any of them
all such disappointing leaders we've had
mediocre people at
best
okay let's take some other
questions okay shaswat mukarji says how
did Adolf Hitler lose the war is it
because of his attack on the Soviet
Union not spending on submarines but but
big on water ships uh okay last the last
uh part of the question made me raise my
eyebrows not spending on
submarines the Germans invented the
submarine the Germans
had truckloads of submarines they were
called SE boots and boots uots they had
hundreds of uots the
Germans so it's not like they did not
spend on submarines they had the best
submarine Fleet in the world
um they also had reasonably good good
big warships and all that why did adol
Hitler lose the war um he did not lose
the war because of his attack on the
USSR one of the reasons was that he did
not go straight for Moscow he went
for the South the South uh southern part
of Russia the Ukraine Crimea region
which is rich in oil and gas and Hitler
thought if I secure this part of Russia
I'll have uh I have no problem accessing
oil and gas for the remainder of the war
so he operation Barbarosa started with
the German
Army uh going for Moscow and then they
decided to go southwards instead of
going for Moscow right away that's one
factor and
then well there there that that
strategic miscalculation that strategic
blunder was
rewarded by all the miseries that the
Russian winter brings upon you
so uh the Russian winter was not the
reason for their loss in Russia it was
the punishment for a big
mistake um
then they did not go for see they took
the Germans took all of Europe they took
they took France they took everything
else but they waited too long to make a
move on the
UK they should have done it perhaps
that's another reason so multiple
reasons there but the real reason is
that the
US came into the
war um and the US had essentially
inexhaustible resources because of they
they occupy an entire continent
essentially North America they also had
access to the Canadian Resources Canada
is a vasal state of the US it's like a
puppet of the US so they have an entire
continent's
resources and the war effort or
kickstarts their economy again they were
know 1930s were the big recession of the
US the war the war actually kickstarts
the economy and the Americans very
rapidly established power projection
capabilities that were beginning to
become Global in nature they started
controlling all the supply chains and
everything that is you know these
logistical things are the critical
aspects that change the outcomes of War
so uh I think uh Hitler lost the war
because of a number of strategic
mistakes
miscalculations also because a p a new
power the US with inexhaustible
resources entered the war the Germans
could not damage the US US Homeland
could do a thing about it but the
Americans could damage Germany and
slowly slowly they crept forward after
The Landings in
Normandy uh
so uh and also because Adolf Hitler made
too many enemies he kind of did the same
mistake made the same mistake is
Napoleon trying to fight everybody at
the same time once you
establish control over certain
territory instead of holding it you keep
on expanding further and further and
outwards and outwards eventually you're
going to run out of space to expand
especially when you are a nation with
not that great amount of control and
resources so multiple mistakes you
there's not there's no one reason why
Germany Nazi Germany lost the war It's a
combination it's a superposition of
multiple mistakes all together that
contribute to their defeat that caused
the
defeat abinash aara says do you think
India's GDP per capita would be anywhere
close to top economies anytime soon
obviously it's impossible to have it
anytime soon India's GDP per capita is
what
$1,000 per person $2,000 I'm not sure
what it is let's Google
it let us Google India's GDP per capita
okay
let's go to
Google India GDP per
capita okay wow I'm pleasantly surprised
it's 2410
2,400 US dollar per capita and we are
being compared with compared with
Bangladesh and Pakistan fascinating
comparison what about China GDP per
capita China is 12 so it's about five
times that of India right India is 24
China is
12.7 so about five roughly roughly five
times that of India what about the US
the US
is excuse me 76 now this is a top
economy right us is is a top economy
what about the UK UK is 46 boohoo
Japan what about Japan sorry not Japan
it's Japan the Japan is 33 what about
the sing
Singapore Singapore 82 good God
UAE
53 okay one last one
Russia 15 okay so when we talk about top
economies let's just take the example of
the US it's
$76,000 per capita India is
2,400 do you think India can go from
$2,400 per capita to $76,000 per capita
anytime
soon you I think you can answer the
question yourself
now not anytime soon it's going to take
decades it's going to take generations
of hard grind hard labor for India to
achieve this if it is ever going to be
achievable at all at all then also
there's no
guarantee that is the situation today
you have to be realistic and that's the
reality
honey Sharma has been asking this
question for many weeks so let me take
it and there's a reason I did not take
this question before because because
I've answered the
question could India fake an attack on
itself to enter Bangladesh similar to
operation North fors in 62 this might
prevent Uncle Sam from opposing
sanctions and India might have a changed
map India cannot do a thing against
Bangladesh right now whether India faces
a fake attack or a real attack or
whatever it
is the Americans don't care about what's
right or what's wrong they care about
the balance of
power I have answered this question
multiple times India is not in a
position to do anything about Bangladesh
and and redrawing the map like you're
saying anytime soon as long as
Bangladesh is a us wasal and it's a
newly minted us
wasal even if let's say hypothetically
in a fictional Universe India fakes an
attack upon itself from Bangladesh you
think that the Americans oh yeah now you
have right just cause for war please go
ahead and change the map you think
that's how the world works the US
doesn't care about who's right or who's
wrong the US wants a certain balance of
power in the
region do you think the coup in
Bangladesh was was was the right thing
to do do you think it was legitimate do
you think uh it's it's Justified no it's
not but the Americans still did it you
think that they care about right and
wrong so the point is we have to be
realistic we have to understand how the
world really works the world doesn't
work on the basis of who's right and
who's wrong in the world there is no
justice in the world if you want Justice
you have to make your own Justice no
one's going to give you justice just
because you say oh they attacked me
first so please allow me to change the
map you think they're G to allow India
to do that no the only way India will
able will be able to in the future if it
ever happens to change the map
the only way it happens if is if if is
if India becomes so powerful that the
Americans can oppose India changing the
map the only solution is India becoming
much more powerful than what it is today
right now India is not a powerful
country now India I do not even consider
it to be a fully sovereign
country because of what's happening in
Manipur and other things as well so
India is a weak country right now just
having a reasonably decent economy
doesn't make you a powerful Nation
there's so many factors involved in this
so the moment India touches Bangladesh
it's going to be problems with the US
understand okay gamer Babu says please
tell how and which nation will help in
Burma operation I am unable to
understand please tell in detail sir
kindly help okay um we discussed Burma
let's kind of go over it again who will
help nobody will help nobody helps
there's no free free lunch in the world
the situation in Burma is
that at least 50% of Burma is under
non-government control it's there's a
civil war going on there are lots of
different let's say Insurgent groups
that are fighting against the burmes
government which is based out of
n uh and the burmes government
historically has been a pro-china
government because China is a powerful
Nation India has never you know quoted
Burma or been able to offer Burma what
what the Chinese can offer so the burmes
government the military government has
historically been pro-china there was a
beast brief time when onang sui's
democratically elected government was in
power but it's no longer there it was
kind of a pro us kind of government to
some extent but then okay that's a whole
different issue so now there's a civil
war raging in b
and all these Insurgent groups or
anti-government groups tribal groups
most of them are supported by the US and
they are somehow
getting endless quantities of arms and
ammunition and this is affecting Manipur
also it's something the US is doing so
right now there's a civil war happening
in Burma it's essentially a proxy war
between the US and China and it's not
causing terrorist activities on Chinese
soil thus far as far as we know but it
is certainly affecting Manipur in a
horrible way that is the situation in
Burma now okay now perhaps I'm beginning
to understand your question gamer Babu
so now I said that this solution to the
Manipur conflict to the foreign
terrorism in Manipur the solution lies
outside of India
right because the terrorists are coming
from Burma the terrorists are the
cookies who are not even burmes they
don't speak the Burmese language they
don't practice burmes culture they don't
even respect the burmes culture they're
not even burmes okay cookies and they
want to create a new nation cooki land
for
Christ so I said that the solution to
the problem is a military operation
outside of India which is Burma right
but this will have to happen with
another nation that is aligned with
us and the question now I'm able to
understand the question gamer Babu is
saying which nation will help in the
Burma oper
well it's obviously not Burma Burma is
under threat Burma is in crisis Burma is
under attack which Other Nation did I
just mention just
now is affected by by the Civil War in
Burma which Other Nation apart from
India is affected by the Civil War in
Burma I just answered your question
that's your answer if it ever happens no
guarantees okay if you want you can
rewind this after this Liv stream is
over I gave the answer just
now
okay Malik said says why is no one
talking about Putin using bomber in
Ukraine allegedly killing 15,000 troops
well I am not talking about it because I
haven't heard of
it am I out of touch with what's
happening in Ukraine I I myself haven't
heard of this Putin using a bomber in
Ukraine allegedly killing 15,000
troops it's not
impossible and if such a huge loss of
troops
happens it will obviously be Ukrainian
troops with some Western troops thrown
in obviously smattering perhaps or maybe
I don't know what it is so I haven't
heard of this this
far and maybe after this live stream
I'll go and check it out where have you
heard this let me let me quickly go and
do a Google search
um Putin using bomber in
Ukraine
15,000
casualties
really um watch Putin's Kami Kaz Kami
Kaz 15,000 Ukrainian soldiers there are
some YouTube videos that talk about
this okay let's let's let's try and do
some tools and any time let's say the
past
week okay the Russian Ministry defense
Ministry announced it has
inflicted nearly 15,000 casualties on
Ukrainian troops and destroyed over 122
tanks since the kurus in inion began in
August and the Russian counter offensive
took place took shape early this month
so it's not a single strike and it's not
a bomber it's a multiple it's it's
multiple uh weapons that have obviously
been used it's it's the it's once again
let me put that back on the screen it's
not a single strike it's not a a
strategic bomber or any kind of bomber
it's 15,000 casualties roughly on
Ukrainian
troops in the ongoing fighting since the
kurus incursion began okay so that's the
deal um and yeah so I think that's what
the time of India seems to be saying
here 15K troops killed in put Russia's
kskk Revenge okay okay uh I get what
you're saying Okay so this okay I was
not aware of that particular claim that
they have that there's been 15,000
roughly casualties on the Ukrainian side
uh but yeah that's the nature of warfare
people it's troops die
unfortunately uh so yeah so it's not
bombers it's it's I'm sure this
artillery there's this hand toand
fighting there is sniping there is Small
Arms Small Arms firing
grenades all kinds of weapons all kinds
of weapons that would have cumulatively
caused these casualties in case this
claim is
correct okay so in Warfare in this war
especially there's been so much
disinformation misinformation claims and
counter claims it's really hard to know
whom to
believe at the end of the day you have
to either believe someone's claim or not
the Americans say that 300,000 Russian
troops have died they made this claim in
like we we just saw this right scrolling
one of the things one of the one of the
headlines was that that 200 or 300,000
Russian troops have died in one year
that's the claim they had made in 2023 I
think that's a nonsensical claim because
Russia is stronger than than than before
Russia is stronger than ever and they
clearly have the upper hand in the War
uh so those claimes uh clearly are are
hard to believe this claim that 15,000
Ukrainian troops roughly have died after
since August it is more
believable more believable but once
again it's a claim and nobody I mean
there's no way to corroborate it so
that's the situation in war it's the fog
of War it's always hard to know what to
believe whom to
believe Vikram geopolitical says why are
Southeast Asian countries not so
significant in global politics despite
having a good population in economy
because it doesn't it's not enough to
have a big population in a good economy
you look at
Brazil huge Nation big reasonably big
population top 10 economy geopolitically
insignificant with all due respect to
Brazil I like Brazil big I really like
Brazil but unfortunately that's the case
it's not enough to have a big population
it's not enough to have a big
territorial area it's not enough to have
have a big economy your military muscle
is extremely
important your power projection ability
capabilities are extremely important and
it
doesn't it helps to have nuclear
weapons and when it comes to the
Southeast Asian Nations once again let's
go to the map which is the largest
Southeast Asian Nation we'll discover
together I think I know the answer but
let's discover together which is the
biggest Southeast Asian Nation clearly
it's Indonesia right large territorial
area large Maritime area as
well big
population and reasonably good
economy but militarily I'm not sure how
powerful Indonesia is clearly it's not
very powerful militarily I'm sure they
can defend their territorial integrity
and so
on but that's about it they don't have
nuclear weapons and they don't have the
the biggest military most powerful
military uh when it comes to other
Southeast Asian Nations like uh Thailand
Vietnam Etc Philippines Burma we spoke
about Burma look these are reasonably
small nations with reasonably small
economies GDP per capita will be
reasonably good compared to India I'm
sure living standards will be better
than India for sure for a variety of
reasons but no nuclear weapons no power
projection abilities beyond their own
you know near
abroad and no all all of that combined
so that's why they are not so
significant and and obviously no power
projection abilities so these are the
reasons why they are not significant in
global geop
politics
okay let's uh
okay Rahul says do you think Prime
Minister Modi is visiting the US to
meddle in the election in some
way
look India will have to be a really
really different kind of country before
it's able to meddle in US
elections
um no Mr Modi is not going to the US to
medal in their
elections nobody dares medal in US
elections only the American American
establishment medals in US elections
so uh they do it themselves they don't
need others Outsiders to do that Prime
Minister Modi is going to the US to
touch Bas again with the US
establishment whoever is really running
the country the US and try and find some
way forward in which which is beneficial
to both Nations and which doesn't hurt
in and harm India too much because right
now the US is all
Hammer against India at least it's it's
doing regime change operations in
India's neighborhood it's it's it's
bleeding India in Manipur it's
it's doing a regime change or trying one
in in Burma it's trying to create a new
artificial Christian Nation kilan for
Christ um it's got Pakistan as its loyal
wasal on the on the on the Western
frontier so much the US is all powerful
right now I think they are they have
become way more powerful than we can
imagine perhaps the Americans I think
ever since artificial intelligence has
been announced I think they may have uh
AI systems that are at least 100 times
more powerful than the best system that
we are aware
of which would give them Godlike
capabilities maybe it's AGI or maybe
it's ASI AGI means artificial general
intelligence ASI means artificial super
intelligence so maybe they have God
level capabilities already and that's
giving them this incredible level of
confidence and uh world leaders would
know about what's going on so and maybe
they have other technologies that we're
not aware of maybe all the UFOs that
only visit the us maybe they are
lockhead Martin technology or Boeing
technology who knows maybe Boeing is
investing it's good workers in in these
things so maybe the US has already
become
invincible uh that's a
possibility so uh or maybe it's not we
don't know it's all speculation that I'm
doing right now but Mr Modi is going to
the US to why look why does a world
leader or the leader of a Nation do
anything their job is to serve the
national interest that's it right every
single thing a national leader does must
in some way or the other serve the
national interest so if Prime Minister
Modi is going to the US he's going on a
trip designed to hopefully serve India's
national interest in some way maybe by
getting the US to back down a little bit
on on squeezing India
maybe finding some common ground on
something so essentially you going to a
much more powerful Nation so you have to
go as a supplicant and hopefully get
something out of it that's the long and
the short of it that's why is visiting
the us we dare not medal in their
elections the very suggestion is well
I'm glad you made me
smile okay
lipon bua says yesterday chakma Buddhist
hajong and tripuri Hindus were killed in
rangamati diala and kagar sadar in the
chagang division of Bangladesh this is
something that's been happening for
decades the the the chagang region
should never have been part of
Bangladesh of East Pakistan why did our
so-called founding
fathers even
accept Chittagong being part of of East
Pakistan why did they even accept silth
being part of East Pakistan these are
not Muslim dominated areas we gave it
up the the deal is that the British
wanted these regions to be part of East
Pakistan especially
Chittagong because if Chittagong becomes
part of India then India's Far East has
access to the Sea and East Pakistan gets
cut off on both sides hemmed in by India
so that's why the British wanted the
chagang region to be part of East
Pakistan and our wonderful leaders of
that time of the 1940s era they went
along with all these demands of the
British which was extremely detrimental
to India's national
interest so ever since the Buddhists and
Hindus who who reside in this
region in the Chong in the Chong region
they have been persecuted they have
endured Decades of persecution I'm not
sure if anybody is still alive I'm
surprised that they're still able to
kill Hindus and
Buddhist chakmas and all trues and all
that so that is something that's been
going on for a very long time I think
during shika's time it was kind of not
so bad but now we have Bangladesh which
has turned into East Pakistan again so
it's it's resumed and they'll probably
ensure that H I don't even want to say
it
so so there you have it we have East
Pakistan that's been recreated so all
these things will happen there is an
ongoing genocide of Hindus and Buddhists
happening in East Pakistan right now
right now as we speak we sitting
wherever we are wherever we are with our
families in our nice houses comfortable
eating good food
and and these people our
people they don't know if they'll see
tomorrow
that's a
situation and what can India do right
now not a thing tells
you kind of puts India's power hard
power as a nation in perspective doesn't
it
okay let's see what other
questions okay let's see this one
Sam Sam Doha RI says the UK was the
leader of the world the most powerful
power most powerful entity before the
second world war but after the second
world war how is the US the leader of
the world and yet how is the UK a friend
of the us where the UK's power goes to
the US you have to understand to answer
to understand the answer to this
question you have to understand what
constitutes
power power it's not like the UK gave
gave its power to the US that's not what
happened the UK was under siege during
the second world
war there was a time during the second
world war when the most powerful
nation in
Eurasia was Germany
and they had defeated everybody else
theyve taken they had taken France they
taken everybody conquered everybody only
the UK was left in Europe so at that
point in time the UK was not the leader
of the world it was nothing it was
clinging to Freedom somehow there were
nightly Blitz GRE raids on London on on
the UK the German by the German
L the UK was no leader of the Free World
of the world at the time Germany was the
most powerful Nation
the UK was essentially reduced to almost
helplessness it was surviving because
the Americans let's go to the map the UK
was able to survive all these all these
years because the Americans were sending
in supplies through the Atlantic Ocean
to the UK the Germans knew about it and
this this was causing friction between
Germany and the
US so the UK was essentially reduced to
nothingness during the second World War
they still had their outposts in various
parts of the world they had Australia
New Zealand they had their supply chains
in various Outpost Colonial Outpost and
whatnot across the world but that is
something the Americans took
over the Americans were still a free
Nation they had access to the resources
of an entire continent North
America they were too far away from
Germany or anybody else that anybody
could touch them or harm them and then
they decid to enter the
war and they took over from the UK their
entire Global Machinery power power
projection Machinery Supply
chains assets everything they just took
it over because they could and the UK
had no option and that's how the us
became the leader of the
world and they gave so
much resources and whatnot to the UK
that the UK went deep into
debt and they were repaying the debt to
the us until the 21st century the first
decade of the 21st century that's how
long they to repay the debt that's how
much that's how deep in death the UK
debt the UK was to the
US and the US took over the entire
Global Supply chains and machinery and
assets and resources and everything that
the UK had they just took it over and
what could the UK do about it nothing
because the US was too powerful
that's how the world works the UK the US
just took everything over and the UK in
1956 tried its last Gambit the sus
crisis and the Americans just shut that
down and that was the official demotion
of the UK to the ranks to the rank of a
second or third rate Global power so now
the UK obviously they have to save face
so they said that we are the allies of
the US friend of the US they're not
allies or friends of the US they are a
wasal of the
us as long as Margaret Thatcher was in
power the UK was kind of independent or
large extent it was independent but
everything changed with the with with
Tony Blair coming to power you know what
people uncharitably called called Tony
Blair they called Tony Blair George W
Bush's lap
dog some would say it's uncharitable
some would say it's welld deserved but
ever since that happened
the UK became well just like a white and
Rich version of Pakistan for the US
aasal that's it so power comes from
Supply chains power projection hard
power military power economic power
nuclear power all that and the US has
that in abundance all of that put
together all right
um mcloven says the 19 93 Japanese anime
movie of ramayana is re-releasing in 4k
next month in movie theaters across
India in October a great gift from Japan
I agree I haven't seen that and I will
make sure I go to a movie theater
somewhere near me and watch
it because it's I I I hear it's one of
the best ramayan best versions of the
Raman ever made for the
screen and I think it will be released
in multiple languages English Hindi uh
Tamil Telugu not sure about Canada but
multiple languages so I certainly look
forward to watching it and in case the
viewers audien are not aware of it
please please do go and watch
it uh yeah one of the best versions of
the Raman ever made that's what I
hear Satish says how do you see illegal
immigration migration in Europe we are
seeing this phenomenon aren't we illegal
immigration illegal migration all across
the Western world into the Western world
it's happening in the US the southern
border has been opened up by the Biden
regime and millions of of individuals
have been allowed to cross over into the
US and they've been they've been allowed
to they've been they've been transported
to various parts of the US far and wide
and they will all all vote Democrat
obviously right uh so
Millions have comeing to the us it's
going to change the US permanently
demographically
culturally politically Etc it'll
permanently change the US what about
Europe millions of military age men
single men without families are being
brought into the various nations in in
Europe France has had this problem for a
long time it's getting worse Italy has
had this uh the Nordic Nations Denmark
Sweden Etc good God they they used to be
really peaceful Nations now there's
rampant crime of various kinds horrible
kinds all across there UK oh good God UK
uh things are really bad in in the UK in
all these various European nations
illegal immigration clearly illegal it's
against the law but it's being being
allowed
and it looks like the UK the EU
leadership in Brussels has quotas for
every nation and they have to abide by
these quotas and all
that we are witnessing probably the
largest mass migration in known
history recorded human history and we
are not even recognizing that this is
such a pivotal moment in history the
entire demographic and cultural Destiny
of the western world is being Rewritten
right now it's been re-engineered right
now by some
power one wonders what their power
is but the West is is destroying
itself so how do I see this well it
doesn't affect me of course it it it
affects the whole world actually it it
is going to affect the whole
world in so many
ways first of all we in the past used to
look up to the West for its high
standards
right the West had high standards living
standards rule of
law uh efficiency of the governance
machinery and so on so forth so many
things you you don't you see a
significant decline of those standards
happening right
now in in the west so so much is going
to change in the West in a few years
Indians you know Indians are always
wondering which country do I go to
settle down
in in the past it used to be the US
Canada Australia
England sometimes New Zealand otherwise
various uh European nations now today I
I'm sure Indians are wondering where on
Earth do we go to settle down obviously
we want to escape India because of it of
its abysmal living standards and all
that corruption lack of
Merit uh okay so so where do I go to
settle down in the past if you were from
Punjab it used to be
Canada Canada is I wonder if Canada is
that attractive and is still that attra
attractive us has all these problems
social problems societal
problems so it's we are witnessing the
probably the
largest
migration in recorded history it's being
engineered this is the largest it's also
the largest uh
example in history of of demographic
re-engineering cultural social
demographic religious political
re-engineering and imagine the power
behind it how powerful it has to be to
do
this on on on multiple continents even
Japan is being forced to absorb UND
desirable
immigrants Japan is being forced into it
Japan is going to be destroyed by
this one of my favorite countries Japan
is going to be destroyed by this they're
in the process of destroying Japan
demographically they already destroyed
it economically haven't they now they're
destroying it
demographically South America thus far
is immune from
this let's see how it goes because the
South American nations are all vasal of
the
US they can't do a thing against the
US so my point is we are witnessing the
largest demographic cultural social
political religious re-engineering in
human history we are living through it
right now we witnessing one of the
largest mass migrations in in human
history and imagine how powerful you
have to be to be able to engineer this
all across multiple
continents so yeah that's how I see
illegal migration not just Europe but
everywhere
else Rahul THV says pleas look please
talk about the recent ey worker suicide
case why no worker laws for white colar
workers we are made to work 12 hours a
day no week days and then give 25% tax
and then income tax okay so I am not
aware of this case I have heard
something
vaguely but I don't know the specific
details okay but the larger picture I'm
aware white color workers so there are
two kinds of technically workers blue
colar white and white collar blue colar
workers are those who work in in labor
right construction work and physical
labor and stuff and white color are are
the are the workers are the workers who
sit in small little prisons in offices
those little cubicles and you work on a
on a lap laptop or computer or
whatever um whether it's in it or
whether it's in um in what insurance or
whatever so I've been that in the past
I've done that I've I've paid my dues
I've been a cyber coie myself you know
working for somebody 12 hours a
day um and yes in India we don't have
any worker laws labor laws as far as I
know for white collar workers your
employer can make you work as much as
they want
so when I was a cyber coie back in the
day it was not unusual for me to work 12
days
easy I was lucky if I got one weekend
off one one one week one one day in the
week off I remember there was a time
when I worked like 24 days in a row 12s
12 plus hours a day when you're young
when you have one precious job you have
few
options you can't do a thing you got to
say yes to whatever they say they're
going to keep on exploiting you and you
to allow them to do that because
otherwise you're
jobless and I'm sure that's what people
face today in India you made to work 12
hours a day sometimes more sometimes you
do night shift sometimes you work more
than 12 hours a day sometimes you work
weekends overtime is normal if you leave
at 5:00 p.m. 9 to5 then you are you're a
slacker you should leave at least at 8
or 9: p.m. then then you are an average
worker but if you stay till 12:00 p.m.
in the night midnight then you are a
good worker and you don't do it every
day that's the kind of attitude you have
managers in India are are are
sadists very often I've had a few of
those managers back in the day pathetic
people very cruel very evil they'll
micromanage everything they
will yeah I I've seen a few of those and
I hear a lot of horror stories these
days so um things are really bad there
is there seems to be very little
regulation and uh so it's kind
of one can see that some people would be
driven to taking
very rash and
harsh
decisions such as what's happened I'm
sure there are many more cases like this
but somehow this case is being spoken
about and you see something similar in
the education system where you
you're trying for what a government job
IAS job or whatever or you want to get
into the IIT and you to do it over and
over again and you go to Cota or
whatever and so many kids they give up
on their lives because of the
conditions um so yeah that's the
situation what's the
solution the solution well there needs
to be some government
regulations that employers can't just
uh exploit people
endlessly and Simply Having regulations
isn't enough regulations have to be
enforced in India you have all kinds of
laws but nothing is enforced that is the
problem in India one of the biggest
problems in India is that there is no
proper enforcement of laws rules
regulations but they are enforced when
whoever it is feels like enforcing them
so in selective enforcing so on so the
government has to intervene in these
things you need to have a healthy
working environment people can't be made
to work endlessly non-stop like like
machines like zombies like
robots that's one thing that needs to
happen the other thing is we need to
have a better economy people need to
have options most people do jobs that
they don't really
want their dream job is something
something completely completely
different but they don't have the
opportunity to do that so you have to do
this job or that job so most people
aren't even happy in whatever job
they're doing but it's the only job they
have without that there is no income so
you going to do it compromis in life and
you do that until you're whatever
retirement age and
then so
um things need to
change on the one on the one hand you
need the economy to get bigger stronger
which will create more opportunities for
different kinds of jobs and secondly the
government also needs to
like create regulations and enforce them
that's what I would say I'm not I'm not
aware of the specifics of the case it's
it's very
sad and it's it's something that's
routin unfortunately this sort of
treatment of of workers in
India
okay endan says what will India do if
East Pakistan attacks or does stupid
things on our border are we going to sit
and watch us
backed forces happening to things
happening to us just like Manipur or how
will it be all it depends I don't think
East Pakistan is any in any position to
attack India do something
stupid uh we will see we will definitely
not allow them to cross the border if
they try to and militarily their
strength is nothing compared to that of
India so you need not worry on that
front the problem that can arise from
East
Pakistan is an upsurge in illegal
immigration and uh maybe the creation of
a Manipur like situation somewhere
else maybe well I'll I'll not even take
hypothetical names of places because
yeah why do that so there are multiple
things that can go wrong they
could see shik had had cracked down on
on all the uh training that was and and
training and support that was being
given to the Northeast
insurgents so let's go to the map and
let me explicate what I'm explicating
here so when we when it comes to India's
Far East because of India the various
Indian governments and their horrible
policies that we had towards this region
in the 20th century you had insurgencies
in almost every state in Most states you
had multiple Insurgent outfits who were
fighting each other who were fighting
the government of India and so on it
became so bad that in m in missam that
in 1966 prime minister Indira Gandhi had
to order the Indian Air Force to bomb
terrorist positions in missam so that's
how it was and a lot of the support for
these Insurgent outfits was coming from
East Pakistan which is currently
Bangladesh some of it was coming from
China also the Chinese also wanted to
you know get involved in this because
why not
but a lot of the support arms ammunition
training safe Heavens all of that was
coming in from East
Pakistan and after 71 for some time
there was a lull in this but then there
was the assassination of of mujur Rahman
and then very rapidly this this country
once again became anti-
India and you had the same thing
happening again
support of insurgent groups from
Bangladesh shikh put a put an end to it
to a large extent but now I believe it
could start again so that is the major
pet that we
Face from East Pakistan we already have
the Civil War in Burma and the cookie
terrorists who are pouring in who have
been pouring in from the eastern border
now you may have something similar
starting from the Western border of the
of these of this region of India with
Bangladesh and that is the big threat so
it's going to be so the government of
India the intelligence agencies the
security forces all of them are going to
have their hands full it's going to be a
difficult time for
us and at least this we have seen
coming I mean the regime change in
Bangladesh I'm sure the government of
India would have seen this coming I saw
this coming I put out a video in 2023
about this laying out the exact sequence
of events that was going to change cause
the regime change and it happened
exactly like I said so if I could make
this prediction I'm sure the government
in the intelligence agencies saw this
coming so I'm sure that they are aware
of the
threats that um we face because of the
regime change in Bangladesh and
hopefully we are putting uh you know
things in place to to be able to uh
appropriately and efficiently deal with
these threats that's what I think uh
Manipur is a whole different
situation and it also needs to be
resolved but yeah there we
are Vikram geopolitical says do you
think the US will be successful in
carving out a Christian Nation out of
India Myanmar and
Bangladesh like they did with Timor Le
in the early
2000s see it's like
this
um this cookie land for Christ it will
probably happen in Burma okay okay it
will become a def facto Nation it may
not be a nation that's recognized by
other nations but it will become a def
facto self-governing entity in
Burma and they will try and take some
parts of Bangladesh and make those parts
of Bangladesh ungovernable for the
government of Bangladesh and because the
government of Bangladesh is now a US
puppet regime they may allow that region
to become a de facto portion of
kiland then what these terrorists will
want to do is make large parts of
Manipur and mizoram also not officially
but de facto self-governed or governed
by cookies that's kind of already
happening in Manipur if you go to Chach
chanur the city of Chach chanur
beautiful place it used to be it's been
completely ethnically CLE cleansed of
the indigenous people of Manipur uh
entire houses in and you know regions
have been destroyed burned down
bulldozed and I wonder how much presence
the government of India has there how
much presence how much of a presence
does the government of India have in
Mo and so on I think the whole south of
Manipur is governed unofficially by the
cookies by the by the
terrorists so a cookie land could happen
in this manner so this this region will
technically and officially be part of
India but on the ground you will have
these terrorists running the go the
local governments the local
municipalities they will be collected
the taxes and buying weapons with that
and that's the situation they would want
to
create and that's the problem so it
won't become an official separate nation
it'll be a de
facto separate nation and some parts of
it they want to be part of to be carved
out of parts of India and their
objective is that those regions of India
should have no presence of the Indian
government or Armed
Forces that's the objective I think
it'll be difficult for the US to achieve
this but in the process of trying to
achieve it it's going to make life hell
for the Indian citizens the natives of
this regions who live there that's the
problem davat Singh says what best
advice will you give to someone who will
pursue a career in physics research
India or abroad challenges there's no
physics research in India very little go
abroad I have always been very clear
about this if you have opportunities if
you want to have a good career and you
have opportunities abroad go abroad
absolutely go abroad U you don't have to
sacrifice your whole life and career and
stay in India just to prove your
patriotism or your love for your country
you can love India while working abroad
so I would say that in India there's
very little physics research that
happens the academic system is horrible
it's full of politics unless you are in
maybe the top two or three institutions
for physics research in India you will
be able to do
nothing if you are especially if you
brilliant then they will pull you down
okay the situation is horrible in India
so I would say go
abroad and if you're going abroad and
you want to do physics research if in
case you're in theoretical physics then
you would be well advised to not swim
against the tide especially if you're in
the US if you're in the US you you do a
PhD and if you want to have a career in
theoretical physics you typically have
to take String Theory because there's a
whole Mafia there String Theory Mafia if
you are somewhere else somewhere else in
in Europe or whatever
well my advice is uh don't take a very
difficult PhD
topic take a good advice advisor in
India you can't even choose your adviser
okay the university will decide who is
going to be your adviser in the west you
can choose your advisor you can
interview multiple advisers potential
advisers and decide who is best for you
so choose a good adviser somebody who's
reasonably young not somebody's too old
um and don't pick a very difficult topic
for research get your degree quickly and
then yeah
do and then yeah do whatever is right
for the career
you need to get a job there obviously so
once you are done with a PhD you need to
have a post do and all that and then you
Pro you to get a job offer in University
you need to have a certain number of
Publications all the rules you have to
abide by them you exceed them and you to
learn the local language and all that in
India it's all English English in Europe
you have to learn the local language in
the US it's English obviously UK also so
that's what I would say so my first
advice is go out of
India secondly um
do your research quickly don't pick a
very difficult research topic and make
sure your fundamentals are really clear
really good and obviously it would work
really hard so that's what I would say
my main advice is pursue uh a career
outside of
India until the government of India
cleans up the education system it is no
point there is no point me telling
intelligent and bright young people to
stay in
India okay I would be doing you a great
diser service by by giving you that that
wrong advice so please go out of India
that's that's best for
you mclen says things are really turning
bad for this government do you think
they'll finish this term look I answered
this question before I don't know U
things are difficult look
when in 2014 Narendra Modi was a
completely new phenomenon on the global
stage and the West did not quite know
how to deal with him
they did not know what he was capable of
of they did not know what his objectives
were they did not know what his methods
would
be there was a tremendous amount of of
concern in the west that this guy would
totally transform India the fear was
that he would genuinely transform India
change the Constitution change the
governance system make it genuinely
something that serves the country and
the people transform the education
system promote Indian culture these were
the big
fears well from the Western perspective
none of those fears have come
true Mr Modi has not transformed the
education system he's done nothing to
change it he's not transformed the
governance Machinery it's still all
bureaucrats same same is
stuff he's not done anything to turn
India into cultural superpower he's not
made India Hindu rashtra he's done none
of those things he's only worked on the
Indian
economy so today 10 years after 24 after
2014 today the Americans know exactly
what nendra Modi is exactly what his
government is like what his methods are
what his policies are they know
everything they know how to deal with
this government and now it's no longer
even a government with a full majority
so yes things are bad the heat is on
regime change has happened in our
neighborhood there is there is there are
moves being under undertaken right now
to to take the map of India if not
officially then de facto in the Far East
of India Manipur is under siege things
are really bad for this government and
it's a coalition government so will they
finish this
term I don't
know I hope they do but I don't know
because when you have Coalition Partners
who are outside of your
party they are under no obligation to
obey you and they can always be
influenced by external factors sources
whatever
so hypothetically it may be possible in
the future at some point in time to
influence some of one or more of the
Coalition Partners into withdrawing
support in which case the government
Falls unless somebody else comes to the
aid which I don't know about that so
it's it's a difficult situation for the
Modi
government um they could
have no point talking about what they
could have done in the past but here we
are so I think it's difficult to say
whether they will finish this
term it's not guaranteed that the Modi
government will will finish the
term but I don't know can't make a
prediction Too Many Factors involved in
this okay okay vishak let's take your
question I've seen it a few times okay
question is some insights on US
president Dwight Eisenhower's warnings
about US military industrial complex
being a threat to the US democracy and
what is the US military industrial
complex okay let's talk about that first
the military industrial complex of the
US is the group is is a grouping well
they not group together but it's
those companies
corporations Etc that manufacture
military
hardware and these are enormous
corporations enormous companies and who
who manufactured tremendous quantities
of military
hardware generally it's it's very
complicated very Advanced Hardware costs
millions billions of dollars some of it
I mean a submarine us submarine will
cost a few billion dollars US aircraft
carrier at least 10 billion and various
other arm systems they'll if you talk
about the f35s they cost
in in excess of a100 million
right so very Advanced very
sophisticated Weapons Systems and most
of these are
exported
right and the amount of money that pours
into these these companies coffers is
incredible immense which gives them
tremendous leverage
also it gives them the ability to have
lots and lots of Congress people on
their
side
um House of Representatives people on
the side so they can buy political power
essentially in the
US you know in the US you could say
corruption is legal it's called lobbying
if you do it a certain way it's legal so
you can buy influence you can buy people
out
outright um so these companies have
become incredibly powerful so powerful
that they it is alleged they shape US
foreign policy milary policy and they
essentially want war wars to keep
on going on or happening worldwide so
that they can sell their weapons to
these to various faction that are
fighting Wars countries and so
on so the entire economy of these
companies
depends on
Wars going on all the time in the world
so if there is peace globally then these
companies their their economy will crash
and their profit margins will will crash
to zero and they'll go bankr
bankrupt and these companies are they
probably have all the US politicians in
their pockets so that's the US military
industrial complex and uh it essentially
you could say was born during the
Industrial Rush of the second World War
era it Rev the US economy and that's
when the American politicians everybody
realized that the war is is the biggest
Boon for the US economy because the
1930s were this time of the Great
Depression and the US economy was in the
was was was depressed the time and the
war revived the US economy and turned
the us into
superpower and
that's something that Dwight Eisenhower
realized and he when he was Dem meting
office
he made this famous speech in which he
warns he issues this warning about the
US military industrial complex about how
it's a it can be a threat to US
democracy and all
that uh and he was right obviously I
would I from my perspective the last
truly democratically elected US
president
who who truly tried to change things was
JFK Jon F Kennedy and we know what
happened to him what was done to him
and his brother little brother
Robert also ran on the same election
agenda and we know what happened to him
as
well so both the brothers were taken out
after that everybody got the message and
nobody has dared to to rock the boat
ever
since so there we are there we are
that's the US military industrial
complex that's how powerful it is and
I'm sure well it is said that it's part
of the deep State the real establishment
that runs the country we know that the
US is not really run by the president we
know that by now I think even a person
with half an eye can see that the US
president isn't really in charge of the
country isn't really in power it's just
a face it's just a puppet the real power
lies somewhere else in case you have
read the great book The
Hitchhikers Guide to the
Galaxy let's let's Google it what what
Douglas Adams says about the president
of the Galaxy shall we
okay let's let's go to the go to
Google uh okay let's see Doug L
Adams about President of the
Galaxy
um okay let's see
this he was quite a guy Douglas Adams so
here's the quote from the book The
presid president in particular is a is
very much a figurehead he wields no real
power whatsoever he's apparently chosen
by the government but the qualities he
required to display are not those of
leadership but those of finely judged
outrage for this reason the president is
always a controversial choice always an
infuriating but fascinating character
his job is not to wield power but to
draw attention
away from it that is the role the job of
the president of the Galaxy in The
Hitchhikers Guide to the universe okay
it's a fictional book it's a it's it's
it's a book about existential philosophy
disguised as humorous science fiction
essentially but that's what Douglas
Adams said wrote all those years ago and
that applies
exactly to the US and its
presidents Anish says a few months ago I
was in Egypt okay I saw the pyramids and
statues that are 5,000 or so years old I
felt envious and sad the IVC the indust
valley civilization the sarasa Hindu
phase of Indian history that its
geographical extent was larger than that
of kth or Egypt yet not much of that
Antiquity has survived here actually see
here's the deal
in India we did
not invest our resources in building
Monumental architecture gigantic
architecture which is oh inspiring but
serves no purpose for
society imagine in a hypothetical
Universe we our ancestors in the
Saraswati synu phase of India's
civilization they had built colossal
pyramids how would those pyramids have
served
Society in no way
whatsoever so the pyramids that the
Egyptian kings built we don't quite know
what their purpose
was we do not know what their purpose
was
okay there were not tombs of the
Pharaohs not a single Egyptian mummy has
been found in these pyramids but we
don't know what the purpose was but they
exist but imagine what a colossal drain
of the nation's resources these pyramids
would have been the construction and
what purpose itself we're not quite sure
probably it's just to
glorify the the king that's all it was
to represent how glorious and Powerful
he is perhaps that's the purpose of
course um these are gigantic
Monumental um constructions and they are
all inspiring and that's one of the
things that's most famous about Egypt
apart from the Sphinx and it's a source
of Pride for Egyptians
sure but when it comes to the IVC what
you call the IVC or the sarasa Hindu
civilization it was a phase of our
civilization our civilization is
unbroken we had a continuity of that so
the geographical extent of that the
so-called IVC was bigger than Egypt and
Mesopotamia put together let's go to the
map and see what's Egypt and Mesopotamia
one second where's the map here is map
yes so the
IVC or Saras Hindu civilization phase
was bigger in geographical extent then
Egypt and Mesopotamia put together
Mesopotamia is roughly like onethird of
Iraq or let's say whole of Iraq if you
put Egypt and Iraq together that
combined land area is smaller than the
geographical extent of the so-called IVC
that's how big it was and the IVC was
characterized by an urbanized
civilization a fully Urban fully
industrialized
civilization you know
um continuity of culture everywhere
standardization of weights and
measures colossal architecture in the
sense that the ports and the
harbors loal doav Etc are examples were
so
large that they favor that they com that
they compare favorable in size with
today's vishakapatnam where aircraft
carriers can be accommodated that's how
big the ports
were but yeah it doesn't look as
magnificent as a pyramid but it was way
more advanced the Hydro Engineering the
the overall engineering was was beyond
what the Egyptians
had so we had a fully Urban
civilization multi- stored buildings
standardization of weights and measures
in an are larger than Egypt plus
Mesopotamia put together and we have dis
we have excavated less than 2% of the
archaeological
sites
okay more than 98% of of the
archaological sites are
unexcavated imagine what is waiting for
us in there the truth about our our
history is waiting for us in there
someday we'll do it I think it's good
that these are unexcavated at least
nobody is looting and pillaging them and
the artifacts
so that's a deal I know it's it feels
sad to see another country in their
civilization they're having Monumental
architecture we don't have that but we
have some of that we have very ancient
temples very beautiful architecture the
main thing was our culture was such that
we did not waste money on pointless
symbols everything had a
purpose so that's how one looks at it in
context
let let's talk about
aliens vun warrier says NASA committee
who studies UFOs in
Aliens do you think how do you think
this will help in Alien research any
findings based on the studies I am not
aware of this
um uh I am not aware of any NASA
committee on that studies UFOs and
aliens but um let's say they have it
well good for
them um how do I think this will help in
Alien research I I have absolutely no
idea maybe some aliens are on the
committee it will be
fun have have aliens actually made
contact with the US government why only
the US government why not the usbekistan
government why not Namibia why the
US why is it always the US what I think
is that look there seems to be way more
sightings of of unexplained phenomena
but UAP unexplained aial phenomena they
call them right not just flying saucers
or unidentified flying objects but
unexplained or unidentified aial
phenomena uaps there seems to be way
more of that in the US than anywhere
else in the world what from a logical
perspective what does it tell me it
tells me that there is some technology
they have developed that they are
testing in their skies and that's unlike
anything else that is known to the world
and that's why people construe that as
UFOs and aliens but maybe it is Boing
maybe it's loed Martin maybe it's Space
X we thought of thought about
that and because people believe it's
aliens and because you want to keep the
technology secret you say Okay NASA is
going to have a committee that will
study UFOs and
aliens and then you form a committee and
you make them go through the through the
process
but we you know nothing's going to
happen so there's going to be no
findings from these committees because I
think that this technology is actually
secret American Technology that's way be
that's Generations ahead of what the
publicly disclosed technology looks like
that's what I
think feminist Slayer says my ancient
history teacher sir there a guy so it's
a sir so in India if if you a teacher
it's a it's a lady if it's a sir it's
it's a guy it's a man right so my
ancient history sir was saying that
Arians came from Western Europe and they
were immigrants not Invaders and they
intermingled with local people on their
way towards entering India so that's the
new version of the same old Theory isn't
it um earlier it used to be an invasion
Theory Arian Invasion Theory they came
on horses they came with chariots they
came with swords and they had swastikas
and they destroyed and defeated the
local poor black skinned
dravidians and their descendants are the
north Indians and West Indians evil evil
Invaders brahmans brahmanical religion
Hinduism evil cast system bad so on
that's the original story but
archeologists were able to find no sign
of any
Invasion so they had to change the story
and now the Arian Invasion theory has to
be is is is converted into the Arian
migration Theory and so your ancient
history sir is still stuck in the 20th
century concept Arian migration Theory
the Arian migration theory was created
constructed out of the invasion theory
in the 20th
century
so that's something they tried but once
again there is no archaeological
evidence of a migration
none even a migration will give you
archaeological evidence signs
unmistakable signs and evidence of
migration cultural change happens when
there's a migration you will see
suddenly different kinds of buildings
with different architecture and
different religious symbols and
different cultural signs you see nothing
in India you see 10,000 years of
cultural continuity in India so even the
migration theory is false now they have
some genetic arguments and all all that
the Crux of the matter in the Arian
Invasion migration tourism picnic myth
the the the core what is the core claim
of this these theories what is the core
claim the core claim of these theories
is that Hinduism and Sanskrit are
foreign to India that is the core
claim have they been able to prove any
of that how will they can make Claims
can they prove it
I challenge them to prove it prove that
Hinduism and Sanskrit came from outside
of India we have unmistakable evidence
of Hindu practices going back 8 99,000
9,500 years in
India we have unmistakable
archaeological evidence of that hard
evidence so how did then Hinduism come
with these so-called migrants or picnic
goers
3,500 days before today their claims
fall flat on their faces when you look
at evidence and you use logic so your
sir is is a typical Indian
sir okay doesn't think doesn't read
research doesn't apply logic all about
memorize memorize memorize whatever is
in the textbook is is is is word of the
Gods that's the kind of sir you have and
that's what most s and madams and
teachers are
like they they have no real interest in
the subject if you're interested you
will actually want to know what's
happening right now in the field of
research no interest it's just a job for
them just a
job sad lepton bua says Romans copied
the Greek gods but what about the Roman
God Janus Janus Janus whatever you say
was a two- faced
god let's let's let's look up it's a god
of Lies the the the
god it's a god of Lies I think the liar
God Janus
god can you see this a god with two
faces and um what was this what was the
God all
about uh God of transitions etc etc
so yeah so I'm not sure what is the
origin of this God I'm sure it's not
possible to find a Greek origin for
every single Roman God I'm sure the
Romans had some gods of their own that
dates back that date back to the pre
Roman Empire times but I'm not sure what
the that
was and I'm sure that Wikipedia article
makes some claims about what the origin
of this God was but uh maybe it's true I
don't know so yes I agree that that
Janus was not a Greek God because the
Greek gods are the gods of the Vic
Pantheon with some
additions prus is not a viic
God for
sure and there are some some others as
well so they had some of their own Gods
too but most of the Greek gods are from
the Vic
Pantheon
Jupiter sorry Jupiter is Thor Jupiter is
Indra and so many more
I'm sure the Romans see the Romans the
thing about the Romans was wherever they
conquered they absorbed the culture and
made it their own so they did not just
nearly bring wealth back from their
colonies they brought Gods also back
from the colonies and then they would
worship those Gods as
well Mitra ISM for example the worship
of the bull the worship of Mitra Mitra
who is with Mitra Mitra Varun through
Persia through Greece they acquired m
and they had this the the Myra Mysteries
was one of their religious sects so I'm
not sure about the origin of the Roman
God Janus but I'm sure they acquired him
from somewhere they were very fond of
collecting Gods the more Gods bless you
the better it is for in life isn't
it and so
on
okay
okay uh
Max says why do many Indians call women
Madam Madam is a bad word look Madam is
a bad word in a certain context but only
in that
context the origin of the word Madam is
the French word French term
Madame Madame means my
lady
okay my Dame or my lady it is a it is a
term of respect but yes in certain
contexts Madam can be seen as a bad
word you don't need to use the word in
that context
obviously uh know at the end of the day
it's a foreign word for us right
um so it's it's just a consequence of
colon colonization mental colonization
that we use a foreign language and the
words that come along with that so there
you have it but overall it it has a good
meaning okay the root word is is French
madame my lady which is
respectful okay with that I have come to
the end of today's
session lots of questions we've taken
off in various topics I'm glad we
covered aliens and UFOs as well so I'll
I'll end this live stream over here
thank you so much for everybody for all
your questions for your participation
for your viewership apologies to those
of you whose questions I could not take
tomorrow I'm going to take another live
stream in which I will take questions
from the comments so ask questions with
the hashtag ask abijit in the comments
and I'll take take them tomorrow as many
as I can until then take care and keep
raising your standards see you soon bye